Hello, and welcome back. We just discussed the half transform as
大家好 欢迎回来 上个视频中我们提到了霍夫变换
one of the ways to integrate local computation of edges.
它是一种整合图像局部边缘的计算方法
I want to illustrate a second one. And for that, I want to use what we have
今天 我想演示另外一种方法 为此 我将再次使用之前演示过的
seen past, the image processing online facilities.
在线图像处理学报网
The basic idea is here. We are once again in the image processing
基本流程是这样的 我们先进入 Image Processing On Line 的页面
online website, and we're going to be discussing a line
然后探讨一下线段检测算法 (Line Segment Detector)
segment detector that was described by the authors.
这些是算法的作者
And, once again, it's an old technique to produce coherent segments, coherent
这是个传统算法 它不是仅靠梯度检测这样的局部边缘检测
curves in the image, instead of just relying on local edge
来产生区域和连续曲线的
detectors like the gradient. Let's, first of all, illustrate this by
我们先来看一下网站提供的视频
showing one of the videos that they provide in their website.
它可以帮助我们理解这个算法
And, it's going to be very clear already from the video what's happening.
其实 这个视频可以很清楚地解释这个算法
So, let's just open this video, and see how nice it is.
我们来打开这个视频 看看效果
So, you're now seeing edges. You're basically seeing edges all around
现在 大家可以看到图像中有很多边缘
the image. That's really, really nice.
效果挺不错
You're seeing the video and there're very, very coherent curves here in the
还可以看到视频里有很连贯的曲线
video. We don't see gradiants jumping from frame
每帧之间没有大的突变
to frame, and we can actually understand what's
我们基本能看出视频的内容
happening. There is a person here, handing letters.
这里有个人 拿着些字母照片
We can actually read the letters. Look how nice this is.
我们也能辨认出这些字母 看看这效果多棒
A very clear picture of what's happening in the scene, because we have these
整个场景非常清晰 因为线段都比较连续
coherent curves going around. So, this is really, really nice.
这个效果真是相当不错
And what we are going to do now is give a couple of additional examples,
现在我们再看看其他几个例子
really as we have done in the past. Let's just run this demo on real time.
和之前做的差不多 这也是实时演示例子
So, we'll click on demo. And we're going to pick an image. We see
先打开这个例子 再选个图片
here is an image of some chairs. And, I'm going to just, ask the algorithm
可以看到这个图像中有许多椅子 把算法应用到这个图像上
to run it, and here is the result. So, I'm going to shift, scroll this down,
这是结果 我把页面往下拉一点
and then we see the output and the input. And once again, the output is a very
可以看到算法的输出和输入
clear illustration of what's happening in this scene, and we can basically see very
而且 输出的结果清晰地展现了场景
clear curves that describe the objects in this scene.
可以看到 这些线段清晰地勾勒了场景中的物体
Let's see one more example, I think this is really fun. So, let's just illustrate
我们再看一个例子 我觉得这些例子都蛮有趣的
with one additional example, what's going on.
所以就再看一个例子 来理解这个算法
Let's pick this image, and run it.
选这个图好了 然后运行算法
And, once again, let me scroll down. And then, we can see the output and the
我来往下拉一下 现在 可以看到输出和输入
input. The output, and the input.
这是输出 这是输入
And from the output, basically from the coherent lines, that this algorithm has
在输出中 根据算法计算出的连续线条
found, basically we can see the buildings, we can understand the basic
我们基本可以辨别出这些建筑物
objects in the scene. And that's because there's kind of an
可以看出场景中的主要物体
integrations of what are important curves in the scene.
这是因为算法对场景中的重要线段进行了整合
And what we're going to see in some of the future videos is other techniques
我们将在之后的视频中学习其他技术
based on what's called active controls that also provide basically integrations
那些技术将基于主动轮廓模型 (Active Contour)
of the local behavior to give us coherent curves in the image.
并且也能整合局部边缘 从而计算出图像中的连续曲线
Thank you very much. See you in the next video.
非常感谢大家 下个视频再见 // 果壳教育无边界字幕组 | wocow |  luoyetx | 林小七Lynn